<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2023-03-26T20:34:47-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Raghav Sethi</title><subtitle>CS Grad at Virginia Tech</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Building Immersive Web Experiences with x3dom and WebXR</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/x3dom/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Building Immersive Web Experiences with x3dom and WebXR" /><published>2023-03-25T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2023-03-25T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/x3dom</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/x3dom/">&lt;p&gt;Virtual Reality (VR) is an exciting technology that allows users to immerse themselves in a computer-generated environment. With the advancement of WebXR APIs, developers can now create immersive web experiences using browsers that support these APIs. I had been provided with an opportunity this year to work on the feature of integrating WebXR to x3dom open-source library.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.x3dom.org/&quot;&gt;x3dom&lt;/a&gt; is a web-based toolkit that allows developers to integrate 3D content into webpages. By combining x3dom with WebXR APIs, we can create immersive experiences that are accessible through any browser that supports these APIs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The project involves implementing features such as navigation and multiple viewpoints in VR mode. Navigation is an essential feature that allows users to move around in the virtual environment, and multiple viewpoints enable them to see the same object from different angles. By combining these features, we can create a more engaging and interactive experience for users. More details about my contribution could be found in this &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rghv96/x3dom/wiki/WebXR-Changes&quot;&gt;wiki&lt;/a&gt; .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some &lt;a href=&quot;https://metagrid1.sv.vt.edu/~raghavsethi/&quot;&gt;samples&lt;/a&gt;. You may need a VR headset or a browser extension to try VR mode; the details have been provided in the wiki. The samples have been developed by students working in &lt;a href=&quot;https://arc.vt.edu/services/visualization/visionarium.html&quot;&gt;Advanced Research Computing - Visionarium, Virginia Tech&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Virtual Reality (VR) is an exciting technology that allows users to immerse themselves in a computer-generated environment. With the advancement of WebXR APIs, developers can now create immersive web experiences using browsers that support these APIs. I had been provided with an opportunity this year to work on the feature of integrating WebXR to x3dom open-source library.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Artificial Intelligence and Content Ownership</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/EthicsReport/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Artificial Intelligence and Content Ownership" /><published>2022-12-01T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2022-12-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/EthicsReport</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/EthicsReport/">&lt;p&gt;There has been a rapid advancement in AI technology that has led to it being able to generate art, music, and even full-length movies. With the increasing market and industry impact of AI-generated content, it has become necessary to consider the ethical implications of content ownership in this context.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As part of my Ethics in Computer Science course at Virginia Tech, my team was tasked with writing a report on an ethical problem in Computer Science. We decided to work on Artificial Intelligence and Content Ownership thanks to OpenAI making AI a hot-topic again. The report focused on reviewing key cases and literature regarding AI-produced media ownership and determining a potential solution for the ethical implications that could arise. To achieve this goal, various stakeholder perspectives were considered, including those of the software/model builder, artists, hardware team, and company selling the software, as well as the owner of the machine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the key challenges that we encountered while working on this report was determining who should get credit for AI-generated content. Should it be the software/model builder who developed the program? Should it be the artists who select among the generated pieces? Or should it be the hardware team, the company selling the software, or the owner of the machine?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To address this challenge, we examined different scenarios and analyzed the various ethical implications of each one. For example, if the software/model builder is given credit for the content, it could create a disincentive for artists to use the software, as they may feel that their creative contribution is undervalued. On the other hand, if the artists who select among the generated pieces are given credit, it could lead to a lack of incentive for software/model builders to continue innovating and developing new algorithms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also considered the legal implications of AI-generated content ownership. Since current copyright laws were not designed to handle such scenarios, it is necessary to redefine the laws to incorporate these challenges. Furthermore, we examined the potential impact of AI-generated content on the job market, as it could potentially lead to job displacement for those involved in content creation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, the report presented a comprehensive analysis of the ethical implications of AI-generated content ownership. It highlighted the need for stakeholders to work together to develop a clear and ethical framework for content ownership in the age of AI. By considering the perspectives of different stakeholders and analyzing the ethical and legal implications of various scenarios, we were able to provide a comprehensive and nuanced perspective on this important topic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Full Report &lt;a href=&quot;../documents/AI_final_report.pdf&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">There has been a rapid advancement in AI technology that has led to it being able to generate art, music, and even full-length movies. With the increasing market and industry impact of AI-generated content, it has become necessary to consider the ethical implications of content ownership in this context.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Building a Search Engine for Electronic Thesis</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ETDSearchEngine/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Building a Search Engine for Electronic Thesis" /><published>2022-11-01T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2022-11-01T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ETDSearchEngine</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ETDSearchEngine/">&lt;p&gt;Academic institutions the world over are known to produce hundreds of thousands of ETDs (Electronic Theses and Dissertations) every year. At the end of an academic year, we are left with large volumes of ETD data that are rarely used for further research or ever cited in future work, writings, or publications. As part of the CS5604: Information Storage and Retrieval graduate-level course at Virginia Tech, we collectively created a search engine for a collection of more than 500,000 ETDs from academic institutions in the United States, which constitutes the class-wide project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This system enables users to ingest, pre-process, and store ETDs in a repository; apply deep learning models to perform topic modeling, text segmentation, chapter summarization, and classification, backed by a DevOps, user experience and integrations team. We are Team 1 or the “ETD Collection Management” team. During the course of the Fall 2022 semester at Virginia Tech, we were responsible for setting up the repository of ETDs, which encompasses broadly the following three components: (1) setting up a database, (2) storing digital objects in a file system, and (3) creating a knowledge graph. Our work enabled other teams to efficiently retrieve the stored ETD data, and perform appropriate pre-processing operations, and during the final few months of the semester, to apply the aforementioned deep learning models to the ETD collection we created. The key deliverable for Team 1 was to create an interactive user interface to perform CRUD operations (create, retrieve, update, and delete) in order to interact with the repository of ETDs, which is essentially an extrapolation of the work already taken up at Virginia Tech’s Digital Library Research Laboratory. Owing to the fact that the other teams had no direct access to the repository set up by us, we designed a host of Application Programming Interfaces (APIs) which are elaborated in depth in the subsequent sections of the report. The end goal for Team 1 was to be able to set up an accessible repository of ETDs so that they can be used for further research work. This is taking into account how each ETD is a well-curated resource and how it may even prove to be an excellent asset for an in-depth analysis on a certain topic, not limited to academic or research purposes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Full Report &lt;a href=&quot;http://hdl.handle.net/10919/114079&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Academic institutions the world over are known to produce hundreds of thousands of ETDs (Electronic Theses and Dissertations) every year. At the end of an academic year, we are left with large volumes of ETD data that are rarely used for further research or ever cited in future work, writings, or publications. As part of the CS5604: Information Storage and Retrieval graduate-level course at Virginia Tech, we collectively created a search engine for a collection of more than 500,000 ETDs from academic institutions in the United States, which constitutes the class-wide project.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Uncovering Insights from the COVID-19 Open Research Dataset using Data Analytics</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Covid19ResearchDataset/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Uncovering Insights from the COVID-19 Open Research Dataset using Data Analytics" /><published>2022-10-15T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2022-10-15T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Covid19ResearchDataset</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Covid19ResearchDataset/">&lt;p&gt;The COVID-19 pandemic had brought the world to a standstill, and researchers had been working tirelessly to find a cure for this infectious disease. With the rapid acceleration in coronavirus literature, it had become increasingly difficult for the medical research community to keep up. To address this issue, I developed an interactive COVID-19 literature clustering solution using t-SNE, PCA, and K-means algorithm to group similar research articles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dataset&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The COVID-19 Open Research Dataset (CORD-19) is a resource of over 29,000 scholarly articles, including over 13,000 with full text, about COVID-19, SARS-CoV-2, and related coronaviruses. This freely available dataset is provided to the global research community to apply recent advances in natural language processing and other AI techniques to generate new insights in support of the ongoing fight against this infectious disease.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Results&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The interactive tool was able to group similar research articles, making it easier for researchers to discover relevant literature and insights. The solution was also able to identify research articles that were highly cited and popular, indicating their importance in the field.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rghv96/covid19-research-dataset&quot;&gt;Link to Jupyter Notebook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The COVID-19 pandemic had brought the world to a standstill, and researchers had been working tirelessly to find a cure for this infectious disease. With the rapid acceleration in coronavirus literature, it had become increasingly difficult for the medical research community to keep up. To address this issue, I developed an interactive COVID-19 literature clustering solution using t-SNE, PCA, and K-means algorithm to group similar research articles.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Type2Learn - My first Chrome Extension</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Type2learn/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Type2Learn - My first Chrome Extension" /><published>2022-03-01T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2022-03-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Type2learn</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Type2learn/">&lt;p&gt;I am a big fan of productivity tools and always wanted to build a chrome extension. The browser extensions are really powerful as you can run almost arbitrary Javascript over the DOM of any webpage. I had enjoyed practicing touch typing and racing with my friends online. Hitting two birds with one stone, I created &lt;a href=&quot;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/type2learn/fhaenfmnpmhafnbamailokcjjbpmehig?ref=producthunt&quot;&gt;Type2Learn&lt;/a&gt;  - a browswer extension to practice touch typing and concentrate on your webpage. You can monitor your speed, errors you make, and accuracy in real-time!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/demo.gif&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I took some time to launch it as I wanted to create an easy user experience which I believe still can be improved. I launched the extension on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.producthunt.com/posts/type2learn-chrome-extension&quot;&gt;Product Hunt&lt;/a&gt; and posted on online forums to attract some users. It has got 50+ installs across the globe. Do check it out!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">I am a big fan of productivity tools and always wanted to build a chrome extension. The browser extensions are really powerful as you can run almost arbitrary Javascript over the DOM of any webpage. I had enjoyed practicing touch typing and racing with my friends online. Hitting two birds with one stone, I created Type2Learn - a browswer extension to practice touch typing and concentrate on your webpage. You can monitor your speed, errors you make, and accuracy in real-time!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Extensions i ❤️</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Extensions/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Extensions i ❤️" /><published>2021-11-06T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2021-11-06T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Extensions</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Extensions/">&lt;p&gt;Over the years I have discovered some cool and useful browser extensions which help me be more productive both on and off work. I used to use Google Chrome but after being tired of its high memory usage I switched to &lt;a href=&quot;https://brave.com/&quot;&gt;Brave&lt;/a&gt; - a chromium browser. These extensions work on Chrome and Chromium browsers and should be avalaible for other browsers also.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blocksite.co/&quot;&gt;BlockSite: Block Websites &amp;amp; Stay Focused&lt;/a&gt; Stay focused and improve productivity. Easily block any distracting or harmful website. Stop procrastination once and for all!&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://compare.buyhatke.com/&quot;&gt;Buyhatke&lt;/a&gt; Buyhatke helps you shop online and find the best prices on ecommerce sites when you shop there.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/do-it-shia-labeouf-super/miagjfhahnjmnnmhdgelhmbpjgojfnok?utm_source=googleads&amp;amp;utm_medium=adgroup5&amp;amp;utm_campaign=adgroup5&amp;amp;utm_id=adgroup5&quot;&gt;Do It! Shia Labeouf&lt;/a&gt; Let Shia Labeouf motivate you with “JUST DO IT!” monolugue&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/fbfluffbustingpurity/nmkinhboiljjkhaknpaeaicmdjhagpep?utm_source=googleads&amp;amp;utm_medium=adgroup5&amp;amp;utm_campaign=adgroup5&amp;amp;utm_id=adgroup5&quot;&gt;F.B.(FluffBusting)Purity&lt;/a&gt; F.B. Purity cleans up and customises Facebook, letting you filter out the junk you dont want to see. I simply cannot use Facebook without it!&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/google-dictionary-by-goog/mgijmajocgfcbeboacabfgobmjgjcoja?utm_source=googleads&amp;amp;utm_medium=adgroup5&amp;amp;utm_campaign=adgroup5&amp;amp;utm_id=adgroup5&quot;&gt;Google Dictionary&lt;/a&gt; View definitions easily as you browse the web. This extension is recommended for Windows users only as MacOS has inbuilt dictionary.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://grammarly.com/&quot;&gt;Grammarly&lt;/a&gt; From grammar and spelling to style and tone, Grammarly helps you eliminate writing errors and find the perfect words to express yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/jsonview/chklaanhfefbnpoihckbnefhakgolnmc?utm_source=googleads&amp;amp;utm_medium=adgroup5&amp;amp;utm_campaign=adgroup5&amp;amp;utm_id=adgroup5&quot;&gt;JSONView&lt;/a&gt; Validate and view JSON documents in your browser itself! Very helpful to see formatted API response&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/lastpass-free-password-ma/hdokiejnpimakedhajhdlcegeplioahd?utm_source=googleads&amp;amp;utm_medium=adgroup5&amp;amp;utm_campaign=adgroup5&amp;amp;utm_id=adgroup5&quot;&gt;LastPass: Free Password Manager&lt;/a&gt;LastPass, an award-winning password manager, saves your passwords and gives you secure access from every computer and mobile device.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/leethub/aciombdipochlnkbpcbgdpjffcfdbggi?utm_source=googleads&amp;amp;utm_medium=adgroup5&amp;amp;utm_campaign=adgroup5&amp;amp;utm_id=adgroup5&quot;&gt;LeetHub&lt;/a&gt; A chrome extension that automatically pushes your code to GitHub when you pass all tests on a Leetcode problem.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/magoosh-vocabulary/oooelhhaglnggehlocjjmgngfknfclak?utm_source=googleads&amp;amp;utm_medium=adgroup5&amp;amp;utm_campaign=adgroup5&amp;amp;utm_id=adgroup5&quot;&gt;Magoosh Vocabulary&lt;/a&gt; Learn new words every day as you browse! Build your vocabulary each time you open a new tab in Chrome.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://getpocket.com/&quot;&gt;Save to Pocket&lt;/a&gt; Pocket’s Chrome extension is the easiest, fastest way to capture articles, videos, and anything else you find on the web.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/save-to-google-drive/gmbmikajjgmnabiglmofipeabaddhgne?utm_source=googleads&amp;amp;utm_medium=adgroup5&amp;amp;utm_campaign=adgroup5&amp;amp;utm_id=adgroup5&quot;&gt;Save to Google Drive&lt;/a&gt; This extension allows you to save web content directly to Google Drive through a browser action or context menu. You can save documents, images, and HTML5 audio and video all by right clicking and selecting ‘Save to Google Drive’.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://unhook.app/&quot;&gt;Unhook - Remove YouTube Recommended Videos&lt;/a&gt; Hide YouTube related videos, comments, video suggestions wall, homepage recommendations, trending tab, and other distractions.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Over the years I have discovered some cool and useful browser extensions which help me be more productive both on and off work. I used to use Google Chrome but after being tired of its high memory usage I switched to Brave - a chromium browser. These extensions work on Chrome and Chromium browsers and should be avalaible for other browsers also.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Translating Biometric Data - Improving Biometric Authentication with Generative Adversarial Networks</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/BIOGAN/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Translating Biometric Data - Improving Biometric Authentication with Generative Adversarial Networks" /><published>2018-06-03T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-06-03T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/BIOGAN</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/BIOGAN/">&lt;p&gt;Biometric authentication has become increasingly prevalent in modern security systems, but there are still limitations in terms of accuracy and reliability. One major challenge is the quality of the biometric data itself, which can be affected by various factors such as sensor lens issues or algorithm training. As part of my undergrad thesis at IIT Mandi, I worked on a solution using Generative Adversarial Networks (GANs) to improve the quality of biometric data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Specifically, we focus on fingerprint recognition and propose a method for mapping low-quality fingerprint images to high-quality ones of the same subject using CycleGAN. We also incorporate a Siamese loss function in addition to the cyclic loss to further improve the results. We demonstrate the effectiveness of our approach through qualitative and quantitative results using different GAN models and datasets. Additionally, we show how our approach can improve fingerprint matching using a trained Siamese Network and Minutiae Cylinder code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, our project highlighted the potential for GANs to improve biometric authentication and addresses a significant challenge in the field of computer security.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;../documents/raghav_bachelors_thesis.pdf&quot;&gt;Link to the report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Biometric authentication has become increasingly prevalent in modern security systems, but there are still limitations in terms of accuracy and reliability. One major challenge is the quality of the biometric data itself, which can be affected by various factors such as sensor lens issues or algorithm training. As part of my undergrad thesis at IIT Mandi, I worked on a solution using Generative Adversarial Networks (GANs) to improve the quality of biometric data.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">IITPipe Driver - Building a Custom Kernel Module for Delayed Piping</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/IITPipeDriver/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="IITPipe Driver - Building a Custom Kernel Module for Delayed Piping" /><published>2017-05-23T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2017-05-23T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/IITPipeDriver</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/IITPipeDriver/">&lt;p&gt;Piping is a powerful feature in Unix-like operating systems that allows programs to communicate with each other, passing data from the output of one program to the input of another. However, standard piping is instantaneous, with no delay between the two programs. This can lead to issues if the programs require a delay between them, such as for synchronization or testing purposes. To address this issue, we have implemented a custom kernel module, IITPipe Driver, which provides delayed piping capabilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The IITPipe Driver module works by adding a configurable delay between the output of one program and the input of the next. This delay is implemented using a buffer, which stores the data from the first program until the delay period has passed, at which point it is passed on to the second program. The module is built using the Linux kernel’s module interface, allowing it to be loaded and unloaded dynamically as needed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To measure the performance of the IITPipe Driver module, we conducted a series of tests using different delay and buffer sizes. We measured the time it took for data to pass through the pipe and compared it to the same data passed through a standard pipe with no delay. Our results showed that the IITPipe Driver module added a measurable delay, with longer delays resulting in longer processing times. However, even with significant delays, the performance of the IITPipe Driver module was still comparable to that of a standard pipe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The IITPipe Driver module has several potential use cases, including in synchronization and testing scenarios. For example, it could be used to simulate network latency for testing networked applications. It could also be used to coordinate the timing of multiple programs, ensuring that they execute in a specific order.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Piping is a powerful feature in Unix-like operating systems that allows programs to communicate with each other, passing data from the output of one program to the input of another. However, standard piping is instantaneous, with no delay between the two programs. This can lead to issues if the programs require a delay between them, such as for synchronization or testing purposes. To address this issue, we have implemented a custom kernel module, IITPipe Driver, which provides delayed piping capabilities.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Building a Facebook Messenger Quotebot with Python Flask</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/FBQuotebot/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Building a Facebook Messenger Quotebot with Python Flask" /><published>2016-08-04T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2016-08-04T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/FBQuotebot</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/FBQuotebot/">&lt;p&gt;Facebook Messenger is one of the most popular messaging platforms with millions of active users. In recent years, businesses and individuals have started to use chatbots to automate their communication with customers and friends. Chatbots can help save time and provide quick responses to common questions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alfred - the Quotebot is a simple automated bot that can respond with quotes and images to keywords entered by the user. The bot uses the Facebook Send/Receive API to handle incoming messages and Flask to handle web requests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Implementation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first step in building the Quotebot is to create a Facebook Page and a Facebook App. The Facebook App will be used to access the Send/Receive API. Once the App is created, we need to generate an access token that will be used to authenticate requests to the API.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, we will create a Python Flask web application to handle incoming messages from Facebook. We will use the Flask-RESTful library to create a RESTful API endpoint that will handle incoming messages. The endpoint will parse the incoming message and extract any keywords that match the list of quotes we have in our database.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Quotebot will then use a simple algorithm to select a random quote from a website and send it back to the user along with an image related to the quote.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, we will deploy our Flask application to a hosting service like Heroku.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Facebook Messenger is one of the most popular messaging platforms with millions of active users. In recent years, businesses and individuals have started to use chatbots to automate their communication with customers and friends. Chatbots can help save time and provide quick responses to common questions.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Revolutionizing Visualizations with 3D Holographic Projector</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/3DHolographicProjector/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Revolutionizing Visualizations with 3D Holographic Projector" /><published>2016-06-01T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2016-06-01T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/3DHolographicProjector</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/3DHolographicProjector/">&lt;p&gt;Have you ever found it difficult to analyse and visualise 3D objects in a 2D plane? Do you wish to see dynamic movements of 3D objects in real-time? If yes, then a 3D holographic projector could be the solution to your problem. Holographic projection of objects around us can create easy visualisation of models that can be used in education fields like architecture and modelling softwares like SolidWorks, Autocad, etc. Although there are solutions available in the market, they are either too sophisticated or too expensive. Hence, we aim to build a 3D holographic projector that can revolutionize the way we visualise 3D objects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My team is working on building a 3D holographic projector that will allow us to visualize 3D objects with four different views simultaneously. The pyramid-based technique allows us to project the hologram in four different directions - left, right, front and back. The hologram can be controlled dynamically, and even by hand gestures such as swipe, pinch and grab, or through trackpads that can interact with multiple objects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;../documents/G14_Report.pdf&quot;&gt;Link to my naive course report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Have you ever found it difficult to analyse and visualise 3D objects in a 2D plane? Do you wish to see dynamic movements of 3D objects in real-time? If yes, then a 3D holographic projector could be the solution to your problem. Holographic projection of objects around us can create easy visualisation of models that can be used in education fields like architecture and modelling softwares like SolidWorks, Autocad, etc. Although there are solutions available in the market, they are either too sophisticated or too expensive. Hence, we aim to build a 3D holographic projector that can revolutionize the way we visualise 3D objects.</summary></entry></feed>